<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Audrey Dunham</title>
    <link>https://example.com/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gorkha Earthquake</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/gorkha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/gorkha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The shaking from the 2015 Gorkha Earthquake caused 25,000 landslides throughout central Nepal. Using ground motion simulations, we study the effects of high mountainous terrain on the seismic wavefield and how this influences landslide distribution. Topography is known to both amplify the seismic wavefield through focusing of seismic waves in ridges and de-amplify the wavefield by scatting seismic waves in valleys. Although topographic amplification has been thoroughly studied in both field studies and numerical modeling, it is not well understood for large earthquakes with complex rupture properties. This study illuminates how topographic amplification is distributed for a large earthquake as well as  how this effects where landslides initiate during seismic shaking, at both a large and local scale.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imaging the Forearc of the Cascadia Subduction Zone</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/cascadia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/cascadia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Cascadia Subduction Zone in the Pacific Northwest has the potential to host a M9 earthquake, but generally has little seismic activity in between these large events. Using a dense nodal seismic array, we use local earthquake tomography with small magnitude events to image the forearc in Central Oregon. Understanding the structure of the forearc is important because it can have significant controls on subduction processes as well as hazard along the margin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kashmir Earthquake</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/kashmir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/kashmir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Kashmir earthquake occurred on October 8, 2005, 18km NE of Muzaffarabad, Pakistan, rupturing a 70km long portion of the Muzaffarabad fault to the surface. This event was the most destructive earthquake on the Himalayan margin in recent history, killing 87,000, injuring 69,000, and leaving 2.8 million homeless. ~3000 landslides were caused due to the seismic shaking from this event, and in this study we use numerical modeling with high resolution topography to investigate the link between ground motions and landsliding.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teton Fault</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/tetons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/tetons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a side project that I started in the first year of my PhD in an effort to use local earthquakes to image the Teton Fault in NW Wyoming. We deployed 96 nodal seismometers in the hanging wall of the Teton Fault for 30 days. An undergraduate in our lab detected and located over 100 earthquakes in the region (excluding any coming from the very active Yellowstone caldera). On going work is using machine learning techniques to locate more events and conduct an imaging study of the basin and to identify the structure of the fault at depth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
